# Abdalah Amadou Gueye

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Portoflio | LinkedIn | Github

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience, holding a master degree in Applied Computer Science. I build high-performance **web applications** used by diverse user bases, using React, Next.js, Tailwind, with a strong focus on clean architecture, UI/UX, and modern development workflows.

#### **SKILLS**

- Frontend: React, Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Tailwind, HTML 5, SCSS,
- Backend / DevOps: Node JS, Express JS, GraphQL, MySQL, Supabase, Git, Vercel, Docker, AWS
- Services / Tools: Vercel, Figma, Contentful
- Languages: English (Fluent), French (Fluent), Turkish (Intermediate), German (A2)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, SMAL GMBH, MUNICH, GERMANY JANUARY 2023 – PRESENT

- Developed and maintained reusable UI components with React, Next.js, and TypeScript
- Developed reusable components contributing to a shared design system across projects
- Worked closely with backend engineers to integrate APIs and improve data flow between frontend and backend
- Collaborated on customer-facing features for high-traffic, Accessibility, Lighthouse

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, WORKING STUDENT, FUTURE STORIES, HAMBURG, GERMANY

## DECEMBER 2021 - NOVEMBER 2022

- Maintained and updated the company's Shopify-based website using Liquid and jQuery.
- Built custom Shopify apps using React.js to enhance e-commerce functionality.
- Contributed to UI improvements and optimized code for performance.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, INTERN, OBERTYS, DAKAR, SENEGAL JANUARY 2020 - JUNE 2020

- Developed banking web applications using React.

- Integrated RESTful APIs to enable seamless communication between frontend and backend systems.
- Participated in agile development sprints and supported testing and documentation efforts.

# **EDUCATION**

SRH HEIDELBERG UNIVERSITY - MASTER DEGREE, 2021 - 2023, HEIDELBERG, GERMANY

- Master in Applied Computer Science
- Specialised in Usability Engineering, UI/UX Design

# HASAN KALYONCU UNIVERSITY, BACHELOR DEGREE, 2016 - 2020

- Bachelor in Computer Engineering